A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Middle East and Africa, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia Field Office Files FA643
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1964-1972; I
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/3), Jan-Sep 1970 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/3), Jan-Sep 1970 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence (3/3), Jan-Sep 1970 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/3), Oct 1970-Dec 1971 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/3), Oct 1970-Dec 1971 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence (3/3), Oct 1970-Dec 1971 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence (1/3), 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence (2/3), 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence (3/3), 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Jul 1966-Oct 1966 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Aug 1968 (Box 4)
  - Confidential, 1964-1968 (Box 4)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Closed - File is restricted from scholarly access.
  - Conrad Stucky -- Confidential, Apr 1968-Nov 1971 (Box 4)
  - Confidential -- Reports, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Confidential -- General, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
- Legal and Budget Documents, 1965-1972; II
  - Letters of Agreement, Nov 1967-Oct 1972 (Box 4)
  - Agreements and Amendments, 1965-1971 (Box 4)
  - Contract Between IIE and Ford Foundation, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Agreement Between Ford Foundation and Saudi Government and Project Documents, 1965-1968 (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation Saudi Budget FY 1969, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation Saudi Support Budget FY 1970, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation Saudi Budget FY 1972 (Box 4)
  - Procedures, 1965-1968 (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation Budget, 1969-1971 (Box 4)
- Conference Papers, 1967-1972; III
  - Conference 1 -- "The Administrative Reform Program, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia - An Evaluation and Recommendations for Effective Implementation", Apr 1, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Conference 2 -- "Development Planning in Saudi Arabia" by Raghbir S. Basi, Oct 1968 (Box 5)
  - Conference 3 -- "Development Planning in Saudi Arabia", [1968] (Box 5)
  - Conference 4 -- "Development Planning in Saudi Arabia" A Case Study by Raghbir S. Basi, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Conference 5 -- "Administrative Reform and O&M in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the Ford Foundation's Participation" by Leo C. Pritchard, Nov 1968 (Box 5)
  - Conference 6 -- "Administrative Reform - The Saudi Arabia Case", Nov 1968 (Box 5)
  - Conference 7 -- Saudi Arabia - A Synopsis" [Ernest Spiekerman], n.d. (Box 5)
  - Conference 8 -- "Briefing for Mr. David Bell on the Administrative Reform Program in Saudi Arabia" by Conrad Stucky, [Feb 1969] (Box 5)
  - Conference 9 -- "An Economic Survey of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia", [1968] (Box 5)
  - Conference 10 -- "Politics in Saudi Arabia", Feb 1969 (Box 5)
  - Conference 11 -- "The Administrative Reform Program, Saudi Arabia", Mar 8, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Conference 12 -- "Saudi Arabia Administrative Reform Program - Two Major Problems - Approaches and Prescriptions", [1969] (Box 5)
  - Conference 13 -- "The English Language Program of the Institute of Public Administration" by Robert Mullins, Oct 13, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Conference 14 -- Conclusions Based on Discussions of January 11-13, 1971 Re: Administrative Program Review (Box 5)
  - Conference 15 -- Saudi Arabia Chronology (history) -- "Origins of Arab Forms of Government" and "The Land and Water of Saudi Arabia" Notes Prepared by David Keogh, 1969-1971 (Box 5)
  - Conference 16 -- "Requirements of Efficient Government Operation", Feb 22, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Conference 17 -- "The Administrative Reform Program, Saudi Arabia", Mar 1971 (Box 5)
  - Conference 18 -- "The Administrative Reform Program, Saudi Arabia", Feb 1972 (Box 5)
  - Conference 19 -- Memorandum - "Administrative Reform Program", [1972] (Box 5)
  - Conference 20 -- "The Saudi Arabian Experience: A Cooperative Effort for Achieving Development" by Conrad C. Stucky, May 1972 (Box 5)
  - Conference 21 -- "Proceeding of a Workshop to Plan for a Progress Report - The Administrative Reform Program", Jun 1972 (Box 5)
- Administrative Reform Program Files, 1965-1974; IV
  - "The Program Plan - The Government of Saudi Arabia and the Ford Foundation", [1965] (Box 5)
  - "The Administrative Reform Program" -- Summary Report, n.d. (Box 5)
  - "Administrative Policies and Procedures", Apr 1965 (Box 5)
  - "A Report on the Development of Planning Organization in Saudi Arabia", Jun 1965 (Box 5)
  - "Guide to Examination Planning and Development for the Government of Saudi Arabia" by the Ford Foundation Public Administration Project, Aug 1965 (Box 5)
  - "Ford Foundation Public Administration Project for the Government of Saudi Arabia - O&M - Personnel - Public Works" -- Final Report, Apr 1966 (Box 5)
  - "The Administrative Reform Program, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia - Purposes, Accomplishments and Future Plans", Dec 17, 1966 (Box 5)
  - "Multi-Phase Program Plan for Administrative Reform in Saudi Arabia", Jun 1, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Reform Project -- Briefing Report for David Bell and Background on Saudi Arabia, 1969, n.d. (Box 5)
  - "The Administrative Reform Program", Mar 1971 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- Program Review Outline, Bibliography of Reports, etc., 1972 (Box 5)
  - "Proceeding of a Workshop to Plan for a Progress Report", Jun 1, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- Evaluation Report -- The Organization Sub-system Drafts, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- Evaluation Report -- Notes, Drafts, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- Program Review and Evaluation Paper -- Notes, Memoranda, 1972 (Box 5)
  - "A Progress Report - The Administrative Reform Program, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia - Supporting Studies", Jan 1973 (Box 5)
  - "Administrative Reform Program -- Bibliography of Reports", Jun 1974 (Box 5)
  - Report, n.d. (Box 5)
- Alphabet-Coded Files, 1960-1974; V
  - A -- Saudi Arabian Government Organization Charts, 1967-1970 (Box 6)
  - A -- High Committee Decisions, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - B -- Organization and Management -- General, 1963-1966 (Box 6)
  - B -- Organization and Management -- General, 1967-1968 (Box 6)
  - B -- Organization and Management -- General, 1969 (Box 6)
  - B -- Organization and Management -- General, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - B -- Organization and Management -- General, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - B-1 -- Management Records System, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - B-3 -- Ministry of Finance -- General, 1961-1968 (Box 6)
  - B-3 -- Ministry of Finance -- General, 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - B-3-1 -- Ministry of Finance -- Research and Planning Unit, 1964-1967 (Box 6)
  - B-3-2 -- Ministry of Finance -- SAMA, 1965-1970 (Box 6)
  - B-3-3 -- Ministry of Finance -- Pensions Department, 1969-1971 (Box 6)
  - B-4 -- Ministry of Agriculture -- General, 1960-1964 (Box 7)
  - B-4 -- Ministry of Agriculture -- General, 1965-1969 (Box 7)
  - B-4 -- Ministry of Agriculture, 1970 (Box 7)
  - B-4 -- Ministry of Agriculture, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
  - B-4 -- Ministry of Agriculture -- General, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
  - B-4-2 -- Ministry of Agriculture -- Haradh Project, 1966-1970 (Box 7)
  - B-5 -- Ministry of Commerce and Industry -- General, 1965-1970 (Box 7)
  - B-5 -- Ministry of Commerce and Industry, 1971 (Box 7)
  - B-6 -- Ministry of Communications -- General, 1961-1963 (Box 7)
  - B-6 -- Ministry of Communications -- General, 1964-1968 (Box 8)
  - B-6 -- Ministry of Communications -- General, 1968-1970 (Box 8)
  - B-6-1 -- Ministry of Communications -- O&M Cable Office, 1967 (Box 8)
  - B-6-2 -- Ministry of Communications -- Post Services, 1969 (Box 8)
  - B-6-3 -- Ministry of Communications -- Riyadh Airport, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - B-6-3 -- Ministry of Communications -- Report No. 1, Apr 25, 1964 (Box 8)
  - B-7 -- Comptroller General of State Account, 1963-1967 (Box 8)
  - B-8 -- Ministry of Defense and Civil Aviation -- General, 1965-1967 (Box 8)
  - B-8-1 -- Ministry of Defense and Civil Aviation -- Armed Forces, 1964 (Box 8)
  - B-8-2 -- Ministry of Defense and Civil Aviation -- Civil Aviation, 1963-1966 (Box 8)
  - B-9 -- Ministry of Education, 1963-1969 (Box 8)
  - B-9 -- Ministry of Education, 1969-1971 (Box 8)
  - B-9 -- Ministry of Education, n.d. (Box 8)
  - B-9 -- Ministry of Education, n.d. (Box 9)
  - B-9 -- Ministry of Education, 1969 (Box 9)
  - B-10 -- Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1966 (Box 9)
  - B-11 -- Ministry of Health -- General, 1966-1969 (Box 9)
  - B-11 -- Ministry of Health -- General, 1970-1972 (Box 9)
  - B-11 -- Ministry of Health, 1970 (Box 9)
  - B-12 -- O&M -- Grievance Board, n.d. (Box 9)
  - B-12-1 -- Ministry of Justice, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - B-13 -- Ministry of Information, 1971 (Box 9)
  - B-14 -- O&M -- Ministry of Interior -- General, 1964-1967 (Box 9)
  - B-14 -- O&M -- Ministry of Interior -- General, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - B-14-1 -- O&M -- Ministry of Interior -- Passports and Nationality, 1964-1968 (Box 9)
  - B-14-2 -- O&M -- Ministry of Interior -- Municipality and Interior, 1964-1967 (Box 9)
  - B-15 -- Minstry of Labor and Social Affairs -- General, 1961-1964 (Box 9)
  - B-15 -- O&M -- Minstry of Labor and Social Affairs -- General, 1965-1967 (Box 9)
  - B-15 -- O&M -- Minstry of Labor and Social Affairs -- General, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - B-15-1 -- Ministry of Labor and Social Affairs -- Youth Department, 1968-1969 (Box 10)
  - B-15-2 -- Ministry of Labor and Social Affairs -- Social Security Legislation, 1969-1971 (Box 10)
  - B-16 -- O&M -- National Guard, 1965-1969 (Box 10)
  - B-17 -- O&M -- Ministry of Petroleum and Mineral Resources -- General -- Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - B-17 -- O&M -- Ministry of Petroleum and Mineral Resources -- General, 1965-1972 (Box 10)
  - B-17-1 -- Ministry of Petroleum and Mineral Resources -- Petromin, 1964-1970 (Box 10)
  - B-18 -- Ministry of Pilgrimage and Waqfs, 1964 (Box 10)
  - B-19 -- Public Corporation, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
  - B-20 -- O&M -- Public Works -- Public Utilities, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - B-20 -- O&M -- Public Works -- Public Utilities, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - B-20-1 -- Public Works -- General, n.d. (Box 10)
  - B-20-1 -- Public Works -- General, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - B-20-1 -- Public Works -- General, 1965-1967 (Box 10)
  - B-21 -- Riyadh Amirate, 1968-1970 (Box 10)
  - B-22 -- Riyadh University, 1967-1969 (Box 10)
  - B-22 -- Riyadh University, 1968-1970 (Box 10)
  - B-22 -- Riyadh University -- Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 10)
  - B-22 -- Riyadh University, 1970-1973 (Box 11)
  - B-23 -- Jeddah University, 1969 (Box 11)
  - B-25 -- Petroleum College, 1965-1969 (Box 11)
  - C -- Purchasing, 1964-1971 (Box 11)
  - C -- Purchasing, 1971 (Box 11)
  - C -- Stores/Purchasing -- Ministry of Health, 1971 (Box 11)
  - C -- Purchasing (1/2), 1972 (Box 11)
  - C -- Purchasing (2/2), 1972 (Box 11)
  - C-1 -- Central Purchasing Agency, 1960-1964 (Box 11)
  - C-1 -- Central Purchasing Agency, 1965-1969 (Box 11)
  - D -- Economic Development Planning -- General, 1960-1965 (Box 11)
  - D -- Economic Development Planning -- General, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
  - D -- Economic Planning Development -- General, 1968-1970 (Box 12)
  - D-1 -- Central Planning Organization, 1963-1966 (Box 12)
  - D-1 -- Central Planning Organization, 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - D-1 -- Central Planning Organization, 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - D-2 -- Planning for Growth -- Reports, 1964 (Box 12)
  - D-2 -- Planning for Growth, 1965-1968 (Box 12)
  - D-3 -- Economic Report, 1964-1967 (Box 12)
  - D-3 -- Economic Report, 1968-1970 (Box 12)
  - D-4 -- Economic Planning in Saudi Arabia, 1963-1970 (Box 12)
  - D-4 -- Economic Planning in Saudi Arabia -- Drafts and Reports (Box 12)
  - F -- Revenues, 1964-1969 (Box 12)
  - F -- Revenues, 1970-1972 (Box 12)
  - F -- Revenues, Jan-Jul 1970 (Box 13)
  - G -- Budget -- General, 1964 (Box 13)
  - G -- Budget -- General, 1965 (Box 13)
  - G -- Budget -- General, 1967 (Box 13)
  - G-2 -- Budget Process, 1968-1970 (Box 13)
  - G-3 -- Budget and Related Matters, 1961-1964 (Box 13)
  - G-4 -- Budgeting and Accounting, 1966 (Box 13)
  - G-4 -- Budgeting and Accounting, 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - G-4 -- Budgeting and Accounting, 1970 (Box 14)
  - G-4 -- Budgeting and Accounting, 1972 (Box 14)
  - G-5 -- Budget Message, 1961-1969 (Box 14)
  - H -- Planning Programming Budgeting -- Reports, 1965-1970 (Box 14)
  - I -- Accounting Development Program, 1964-1969 (Box 14)
  - I-1 -- National Accounts, 1967-1970 (Box 14)
  - I-2 -- Statistics, n.d. (Box 14)
  - I-2 -- Statistics, 1961-1969 (Box 14)
  - J -- O&M -- Data Processing, 1964-1967 (Box 14)
  - J -- O&M -- Data Processing, 1968-1969 (Box 14)
  - J -- O&M -- Data Processing, 1970 (Box 15)
  - J -- O&M -- Data Processing, 1972 (Box 15)
  - K -- Standard Time System, 1964-1967 (Box 15)
  - L -- Implementation -- General, 1964-1968 (Box 15)
  - M -- Manpower, 1971 (Box 15)
  - M -- Implementation -- Manpower, 1960-1969 (Box 15)
  - M -- Manpower -- Drafts/Reports, 1969 (Box 15)
  - M -- Implementation -- Manpower, 1969 (Box 15)
  - M -- Manpower, 1969 (Box 15)
  - N -- Staff Committee Decisions, 1963-1972 (Box 15)
  - O -- Executive Committee, 1964-1967 (Box 15)
  - P-7 -- Position Classification and Pay, 1967-Jan 1968 (Box 15)
  - P-7 -- Position Classification and Pay, Feb 1968-1970 (Box 15)
  - P-7 -- Position Classification -- Personnel and Pay, 1964-1966 (Box 16)
  - P-7 -- Position Classification, 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - P-8 -- Contract Employees, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Q -- Seminar -- General, 1965-1972 (Box 16)
  - Q-1 -- Seminar -- Governmental Planning, Budgeting and Control, 1964-1967 (Box 16)
  - Q-6 -- Manpower Seminar, 1967-1972 (Box 16)
  - R -- Training -- General, 1964-1968 (Box 16)
  - R-1 -- Personnel, Oct 1968-Dec 1969 (Box 16)
  - R-2 -- Training -- Personnel Training, 1963-1972 (Box 16)
  - R-3 -- Training -- O&M Training -- Data/Reports/Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 16)
  - R-4 -- Training -- Organization and Methods, 1968 (Box 16)
  - R-4 -- Training -- Organization and Methods, 1969 (Box 16)
  - R-5 -- Training -- Executive, 1964-1968 (Box 16)
  - R-6 -- Training -- Vocational Training, 1964-1966 (Box 16)
  - R-6 -- Training -- Vocational, 1969 (Box 16)
  - R-7 -- Training -- Graduate Training Abroad, 1965-1967 (Box 16)
  - R-8 -- Training -- English Language Program, 1964-1968 (Box 17)
  - R-8 -- Training -- English Language Program, 1969 (Box 17)
  - R-8 -- Training -- English Language Program, 1970 (Box 17)
  - R-8 -- Training -- English Language Program, 1971 (Box 17)
  - R-9 -- Training -- Supervisory Training, 1964 (Box 17)
  - R-10 -- Training -- Clerical Training, 1963-1966 (Box 17)
  - R-11 -- Training -- Agricultural Training, 1964-1968 (Box 17)
  - R-12 -- Training -- Civil Service -- Pre-Service Course, 1963-1968 (Box 17)
  - R-13 -- Training -- Exchange Traineeship Program, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - R-14 -- Training -- Middle Management, 1968-1973 (Box 17)
  - R-15 -- Training -- Civil Service -- In-Service Training, 1963-1967 (Box 17)
  - R-16 -- Training -- Civil Service, 1966 (Box 17)
  - R-17 -- Training -- Development of a Nation, 1962-1970 (Box 17)
  - R-17 -- Development of a Nation -- Reports, n.d. (Box 17)
  - R-18 -- Training Course for Sharia Graduates, 1967-1971 (Box 17)
  - R-19 -- Training -- Budget Analysis Course, 1967-1971 (Box 17)
  - R-20 -- Training -- Custodial Service [PHOTOS], 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - R-21 -- Training -- Wisconsin Program in Administration, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - R-23 -- Training -- Statistics and Training (Box 17)
  - R-25 -- Training Abroad -- Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 18)
  - R-25 -- Training Abroad -- Correspondence, 1968 (Box 18)
  - R-25 -- Training Abroad, 1969 (Box 18)
  - R-25 -- Training Abroad -- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 18)
  - R-25 -- Training Abroad, 1970-1973 (Box 18)
  - S -- Institute of Public Administration, 1963-1968 (Box 18)
  - S -- Institute of Public Administration, 1968-1969 (Box 18)
  - S -- Institute of Public Administration, 1970 (Box 18)
  - S -- Institute of Public Administration, 1971-1974 (Box 18)
  - T -- Conferences -- General, 1965-1970 (Box 18)
  - T-1 -- Regional Conference -- Economic Planning and Public Administration, 1966-1970 (Box 18)
  - T-2 -- Conferences -- Library Conferences, 1966-1970 (Box 18)
  - V -- Project Activities, 1967-1969 (Box 19)
  - V -- Administrative Reform -- Project Activities, 1970 (Box 19)
  - V -- Administrative Reform -- Project Activities, 1971-1972 (Box 19)
  - V-1 -- Project Management, 1966-1973 (Box 19)
  - V-2 -- Project Planning -- Administrative Reform, 1972-1974 (Box 19)
  - V-2 -- Project Planning, 1963-1967 (Box 19)
  - V-3 -- Multi-Year Program Plan, 1968-1969 (Box 19)
  - W -- Annual Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 19)
  - W-1 -- Quarterly Progress Report, 1967-1970 (Box 19)
  - W-1 -- Quarterly Progress Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 20)
  - W-2 -- Monthly Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 20)
  - W-2 -- Monthly Reports, 1970 (Box 20)
  - W-2 -- Monthly Reports, 1971 (Box 20)
  - X -- Iraq -- General, 1968-1970 (Box 20)
  - X-1 -- Iraq -- Al-Hikma University, 1968 (Box 20)
  - X-2 -- Iraq -- Baghdad -- Library Science Program, 1968-1970 (Box 20)
  - Z -- Miscellaneous -- General, 1967-1968 (Box 20)
  - Z -- Miscellaneous -- General, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Z -- Miscellaneous -- General, 1970-1973 (Box 20)
  - Z-1 -- Miscellaneous -- Ford Foundation -- Beirut, 1963-1967 (Box 20)
  - Z-1 -- Miscellaneous -- Ford Foundation -- Beirut, 1967-1969 (Box 20)
  - Z-1 -- Miscellaneous -- Ford Foundation -- Beirut, 1969-1973 (Box 20)
  - Z-2 -- Miscellaneous -- Government, 1964-1970 (Box 20)
- Number-Coded Files, 1963-1970; VI
  - 0-3 -- Travel Study Awards -- Obeid, Rida, 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - 0-4 -- Travel Study Awards -- Sudairy, Turki, 1967-1970 (Box 21)
  - 0-7 -- Travel Study Awards -- Fada, Abdul-Aziz, 1968-1970 (Box 21)
  - 0-9 -- Travel Study Awards -- Sadik, Mohammed, 1967 (Box 21)
  - 0-10 -- Travel Study Awards -- Al-Issa, Sulliman, 1967-1970 (Box 21)
  - 5 -- ARAMCO -- Organizational Structure, Memos Re: Ford Foundation Work with Saudi Arabian Government, 1964-1966 (Box 21)
  - 7 -- American Friends of the Middle East -- Correspondence Re: International Assistance to Saudi Arabia, 1963-1965 (Box 21)
  - 9 -- Riyadh Office -- Administrative Files (including files re: organization of Saudi Arabian government), 1964-1968 (Box 21)
- Miscellaneous Files, 1953-1976; VII
  - Administrative Reform Program, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- J.L. Jacob's Monthly Progress Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- Kingdom of Saudi Arabia -- Project Management (1/2), 1963-1969 (Box 21)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- Kingdom of Saudi Arabia -- Project Management (2/2), 1963-1969 (Box 21)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- Multi-Year Program Plan, 1969 (Box 21)
  - Administrative Reform Program -- Reports, Functions and Objectives Outlines, 1973 (Box 21)
  - Advisory Committee on Social Problems -- For Ford Foundation Consultants and Employees in Riyadh, 1964 (Box 21)
  - Agriculture -- Public Administration and Development -- Middle East (including Pakistan) -- Reports, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Agriculture -- "Selected Agricultural Statistics in Ranked Order for Countries of the Near East Region" Compiled by Oddvar Aresvik and Majed Kreidy of the Arid Lands Agricultural Development Program, Sep 1972 (Box 21)
  - Agriculture, Education, Planning and Administration, Law and Development -- Reports, Memos, 1964-1976 (Box 21)
  - Committee on Computer Use -- Computer Installation and Use, 1964 (Box 21)
  - Cunningham, Louis J., 1963 (Box 21)
  - Education -- Report (Arabic), n.d. (Box 21)
  - Education, Rural Development, Administrative Training -- Reports, Memos, Questionnaire, 1972-1973 (Box 21)
  - Edwards, Wesley, 1974 (Box 21)
  - Electric Tariffs, 1971 (Box 21)
  - (Review of) Electricity Tariffs -- Reports -- Ministry of Commerce and Industry, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Electricity -- Report -- Ministry of Commerce and Industry -- "Sale of Electrical Energy by Saline Water Conversion Office to Saudi National Co. Ltd.", Jul 1970 (Box 21)
  - English Language Program -- Agreements (Institute of International Education and Saudi Arabian agencies), Memos, etc., 1965-1968 (Box 22)
  - English Language Program -- Monthly Reports, 1965-1972 (Box 22)
  - English Language Program -- Personnel Recruitment, Program Guidelines, Course Schedules, etc., 1967-1971 (Box 22)
  - Evaluation -- English Language, [1970] (Box 22)
  - Evaluation -- Health, 1972 (Box 22)
  - Evaluation -- Personnel, 1972 (Box 22)
  - Ford Foundation and Government of Saudi Arabia -- Letter of Agreement, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Jordan Cooperative Organization, 1968-1969 (Box 22)
  - Memoranda Re: Law Decrees and Government Regulations, 1969-1972 (Box 22)
  - Ministry of Interior -- Manpower Training Needs Study -- Reports, 1967 (Box 22)
  - Monthly Progress Report -- To Ford Foundation Beirut -- Re: Ford Foundation Activities in Saudi Arabia, 1964-1967 (Box 22)
  - Monthly Progress Report -- To the Saudi Arabia Government Re: Ford Foundation Activities (incl. Administrative Reform Project), 1964-1970 (Box 22)
  - Monthly Progress Report (consultants) -- Re: English Language Program, 1965-1969 (Box 22)
  - Oman Project -- Paper Re: Health, Nutrition and Child Rearing in Oman (Box 22)
  - Personnel -- Position Classification Plan, Lists of Training Materials Guides, Forms Requesting New Positions, etc., n.d. (Box 22)
  - Principal Training, Government Personnel Training, Rural Development in Jordan and Lebanon, 1965-1973 (Box 22)
  - Program Background Notes -- Re: Programming in the Middle East, 1968-1972 (Box 22)
  - Regional -- Rural Development and Agriculture, 1953-1956 (Box 22)
  - Regional Data Related to Agricultural Development, n.d. (Box 22)
  - Report -- "Administrative Reform in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia Since 1962", Oct 1968 (Box 22)
  - Report (Arabic) (Box 22)
  - Report -- Budget Statistics [Arabic Language] (Box 22)
  - Report (Arabic) (Box 22)
  - Reports -- Position Classification Training Guides (1/2), n.d. (Box 22)
  - Reports -- Position Classification Training Guides (2/2), n.d. (Box 22)
  - Riyadh Office Files -- Logistics -- Memoranda between Conrad Stucky and Rizkallah Sabbagh, 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - Riyadh Visitations -- Materials Prepared for Visits to Riyadh -- Maps, Ford Foundation Personnel Lists, General Information, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Saudi Arabia Quarterly Reports -- Ford Foundation Cooperation with Government, Apr-Dec 1970 (Box 23)
  - Social Science -- Bellagio Conference (February 13-15, 1974), Mar 1974 (Box 23)
  - Stucky, Conrad -- Memos Re: Riyadh Office -- Personnel and Programs, 1964-1969 (Box 23)
  - Stucky, Conrad -- Memoranda -- Riyadh Files, Feb-Sep 1971 (Box 23)
  - Supervisors Training Program -- Instructor's Guide (1/2), n.d. (Box 23)
  - Supervisors Training Program -- Instructor's Guide (2/2), n.d. (Box 23)
  - Supervisors Training Program -- Management Trainers Guide, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Supervisors Training Program -- Supervisor's Guide, n.d. (Box 23)
  - University of Riyadh -- Ford Foundation Study Re: Management and Organization of University, 1971-1972 (Box 23)
- Subject Files, 1950-1975 (Bulk: 1963-1975); 1963-1975; VIII
  - Awards -- Travel and Study -- General Files, 1969-1972 (Box 24)
  - Budget, Accounting, Auditing -- Memos, Reports, 1964-1969 (Box 24)
  - Butler, John A. -- Report on Industrial Education and Training for Saudi Arabia, [1964] (Box 24)
  - Clerical Training Program, 1964-1966 (Box 24)
  - Control and Investigation Agency, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Data Processing, 1969-1972 (Box 24)
  - Development Assistance Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - Development Plan Re: Economic Growth, 1967-1971 (Box 24)
  - Economic Planning, 1963-1969 (Box 24)
  - Economic Report -- Background Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - Education -- General Files, 1963-1972 (Box 24)
  - English Language Program, 1963-1970 (Box 24)